Finding aid for Ethnic and Cultural Communities of Michigan Web Archive, 2010-2014
Bentley Historical Library
Ethnic and Cultural Communities of Michigan Web Archive
2010-2014
Bentley Historical Library
Bentley Historical Library (collector)
2014025 Aa 3 [2014031]
57 archived websites (online; multiple captures)
Web collection of websites created by various ethnic and cultural communities of the State of Michigan, archived by the Bentley Historical Library using the California Digital Library Web Archiving Service crawler from 2010-2015 and the Archive-It web archiving service beginning in 2015.
Websites gathered from 2010-2015 using the California Digital Library Web Archiving Service web crawler and using the Archive-It web archiving service beginning in 2015.
Periodic additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Michigan's ethnic and cultural communities are among Bentley Historical Library's most important topical collections priorities. The topic's priority is based on the Bentley Library's mission as established by the University of Michigan Board of Regents to document "the state, its institutions, and its social, economic, and intellectual development," the historical collecting patterns of the library, and overall collection development priorities in all formats. The process of setting collecting priorities is described by Christine Weideman's "A New Map for Field Work: Impact of Collections Analysis on the Bentley Historical Library" (American Archivist, Winter 1991, Vol. 54 Issue 1, pp. 54-60.) and Judith E. Endelman's "Looking Backward to Plan for the Future: Collection Analysis for Manuscript Repositories." (American Archivist, Summer 1987, Vol. 50 Issue 3, pp. 340-355.)
In selecting web content for permanent preservation, the Bentley Historical Library seeks:
Websites of organizations or individuals whose archives the Library is committed to preserve.
Website that fill gaps in existing collections.
Websites with unique content that documents the work and/or thought process of a person or organization.
Websites that periodically incorporate new content or feature regular updates.
Websites with content that is not likely to be duplicated in an individual or organization's paper records.
As of 2013, the Bentley Library will concentrate efforts on documenting the transformation of Michigan's ethnic communities with a focus on Arab American, African American, Asian American, and Latino communities, focusing on socio-economic conditions, economic and cultural revival, political and civic activities, and religion. In addition to these priorities, the MHC remains open to the consideration of material with great research potential in any area of Michigan's ethnically diverse history.
To learn more about the Bentley Historical Library's Web Archives visit http://bentley.umich.edu/dchome/index.php.
The Web Archive of Michigan's Ethnic and Cultural Communities collection contains archived websites created by various ethnic and cultural communities of the State of Michigan. The websites have been archived by the Bentley Historical Library, using the California Digital Library Web Archiving Service crawler from 2010-2015 and the Archive-It web archiving service beginning in 2015. Access to all websites archived by the Bentley Historical Library is available at: https://archive-it.org/organizations/934.
Web Archives include websites of African American, Arab American, Native American, Asian American and other ethnic communities and organizations who call the state of Michigan home. The collection is especially strong in documenting African American, Arab American, and Native American communities, business, religious, cultural and civil rights organizations, as well as distinguished individuals who belong to these communities.
The year that appears next to the website title in the contents list indicates the date that the website was first archived. Archived versions of the site from later dates may also be available.
African American churches -- Michigan -- Detroit.; African American churches -- Michigan -- Southfield.; African American Episcopalians -- Michigan -- Detroit.; African American judges -- Elections -- Michigan.; African American men -- Michigan -- Detroit.; African American Muslims -- Michigan.; African American public worship -- Michigan -- Detroit.; African American women -- Michigan.; African American women lawyers -- Michigan.; African American youth -- Michigan -- Detroit.; African Americans -- Michigan -- Detroit.; African Americans -- Michigan -- Washtenaw County -- History.; African Americans -- Museums -- Michigan -- Washtenaw County.; African Americans -- Religious life -- Michigan -- Detroit.; African Americans -- Religious life -- Michigan -- Southfield.; Arab American business enterprises -- Michigan.; Arab Americans -- Civil rights -- Michigan.; Arab Americans -- Civil rights -- United States.; Arab Americans -- Michigan.; Arab Americans -- Michigan -- Dearborn.; Arab Americans -- Michigan -- Detroit.; Arab Americans -- Michigan -- Detroit -- Periodicals.; Arab Americans -- Michigan -- Livonia.; Arab Americans -- Periodicals.; Arab Americans -- United States.; Arab Americans -- United States -- History.; Asian Americans -- Michigan.; Baptists -- Michigan -- Detroit.; Boards of trade -- Michigan.; Businesspeople -- Michigan.; Chaldean Catholics -- Michigan -- Detroit.; Charities -- Michigan -- Detroit.; Chinese Americans -- Michigan -- Detroit.; Chinese Americans -- Societies, etc. -- Michigan -- Detroit.; Chippewa Indians.; Chippewa Tribe.; Christianity and other religions -- Islam.; Commerce and industry.; Communities -- Michigan.; Community centers -- Michigan.; Druze women -- Michigan.; Druzes -- United States.; East Indian Americans -- Michigan.; East Indian Americans -- United States.; Education -- Michigan -- Detroit.; Environmental justice -- Michigan.; Ethnic communities.; Ethnic relations -- Michigan.; Filipino Americans -- Michigan.; Fisheries -- Great Lakes (North America); Fishery law and legislation -- Michigan.; Fishery management -- Michigan.; Fishery management -- Great Lakes (North America); German Americans -- Michigan -- Newspapers.; German Americans -- United States -- Newspapers.; Germans -- Michigan -- Newspapers.; Germans -- United States.; Hispanic Americans -- Michigan -- Periodicals.; Hispanic Americans -- United States -- Periodicals.; Housing policy -- Michigan -- Religious aspects.; Hurley, George W. African-American churches -- Michigan -- Detroit.; Immigrants -- Health and hygiene -- Florida.; Immigrants -- Health and hygiene -- Michigan.; Immigrants -- Health and hygiene -- Ohio.; Immigrants -- Health and hygiene -- Texas.; Immigrants -- Health and hygiene -- United States.; Immigrants -- Michigan.; Indians of North America -- Great Lakes (North America); Indians of North America -- Michigan.; Indians of North America -- Periodicals.; Iraqis -- Michigan -- Detroit.; Islam -- Michigan.; Islamic education -- Michigan.; Islamophobia -- Michigan.; Islamophobia -- United States.; Italian Americans -- Michigan -- Lansing.; Lebanese Americans -- Michigan.; Lebanese Americans -- Michigan -- Detroit.; Lebanese Americans -- Social life and customs -- Michigan -- Detroit.; Minorities -- Civil rights -- Michigan.; Minorities -- Civil rights -- United States.; Minorities -- Michigan.; Monasteries -- Michigan -- Harper Woods.; Mosques -- Michigan.; Mosques as community centers -- Michigan.; Muslims -- Civil rights -- Michigan.; Muslims -- Civil rights -- United States.; Muslims -- India.; Muslims -- Michigan.; Muslims -- Michigan -- Periodicals.; Muslims -- Religious life -- Michigan.; Ojibwa Indians -- Michigan.; Ojibwa Indians -- Michigan -- Fishing -- Law and legislation.; Ojibwa Indians -- Michigan -- Legal status, laws, etc.; Ojibwa Indians -- Michigan -- Treaties.; Orientalism -- United States.; Orthodox Eastern monasteries -- Michigan -- Harper Woods.; Ottawa Indians -- Michigan -- Fishing -- Law and legislation.; Ottawa Indians -- Michigan -- Legal status, laws, etc.; Ottawa Indians -- Michigan -- Treaties.; Pacific Islander Americans -- Michigan.; Palestinian Americans -- Michigan.; Polish Americans -- Michigan -- Detroit.; Politics and public policy.; Popular music -- United States.; Potawatomi Indians -- Great Lakes Region (North America); Potawatomi Indians -- Middle West.; Race relations -- Economic aspects -- Michigan -- Detroit.; Racism -- United States.; Religion.; Russian Americans -- Michigan.; Russian Americans -- Michigan -- Directories.; Russkaia pravoslavnaia tserkov' zagranitsei­.; Sermons, American. -- Michigan -- Detroit.; Social justice.; Stereotypes (Social psychology) -- United States.; Taiwanese Americans -- Michigan.; Taiwanese Americans -- Societies, etc. -- Michigan.; Transportation and state -- Michigan -- Religious aspects.; Women -- Charities.; Women in Michigan.; Yemeni Americans -- Michigan.; Yemeni Americans -- United States.; Youth -- Michigan -- Detroit.; Ann Arbor (Mich.); Battle Creek (Mich.); Bay Mills Indian Community, Michigan.; Bay Mills (Mich.); Chippewa Tribe.; Dearborn (Mich.); Detroit (Mich.); Detroit (Mich.) -- Economic conditions.; Detroit (Mich.) -- Race relations.; Flint (Mich.); Florida.; Fulton (Mich.); Grand Rapids (Mich.); Grand Traverse Band of Ottawa and Chippewa Indians, Michigan.; Grand Traverse (Mich.); Great Lakes (North America); Harbor Springs (Mich.); Harper Woods (Mich.); India.; Israel.; Jackson (Mich.); Kalamazoo (Mich.); Keweenaw Bay (Mich.: Bay); Lansing (Mich.); Livonia (Mich.); Manistee (Mich.); Michigan. District Court (36th district) -- Elections.; Middle West.; Mount Pleasant (Mich.); Muskegon (Mich.); Oakland County (Mich.) -- Newspapers.; Ohio.; Palestine.; Pokagon Band of Potawatomi Indians, Michigan and Indiana.; Rām Allāh.; Ramlah (Israel); Saginaw Chippewa Indian Tribe of Michigan.; Saginaw (Mich.); Sault Sainte Marie (Mich.); Sault Ste. Marie Tribe of Chippewa Indians of Michigan.; Southfield (Mich.); Texas.; Troy (Mich.) -- Newspapers.; Wyoming (Mich.); Blogs.; Begg, Victor.; Bledsoe Ford, Deborah Geraldine.; Brown, Al, 1947-; Muhammad, Warith Deen, 1933-2008.; 100 Black Men of Greater Detroit.; African American Cultural and Historical Museum of Washtenaw County.; American Arab Chamber of Commerce.; American-Arab Anti-Discrimination Committee.; American-Arab Anti-Discrimination Committee, Michigan.; American Federation of Muslims of Indian Origin.; American Federation of Ramallah, Palestine.; American Druze Society.; American Moslem Society.; Antiochian Basilica of St. Mary (Livonia, Mich.); Antiochian Orthodox Christian Archdiocese of North America.; Arab America Michigan.; Arab American National Museum (Dearborn, Mich.); Arab Community Center for Economic and Social Services.; Asian Pacific American Chamber of Commerce.; Association of Chinese Americans. Detroit Chapter.; Bay Mills Indian Community.; Chaldean American Ladies of Charity.; Chippewa Ottawa Resource Authority.; Council on American-Islamic Relations Michigan Chapter.; Council of Islamic Organizations in Michigan.; Detroit Association of Black Organizations.; Greater Grace Temple (Detroit, Mich.); Hartford Memorial Baptist Church (Detroit, Mich.); Islamic Center of America (Dearborn, Mich.); Italian-American Club of Lansing.; Keweenaw Bay Indian Community, Michigan.; Lebanese American Heritage Club.; Little River Band of Ottawa Indians, Michigan.; Little Traverse Bay Bands of Odawa Indians, Michigan.; Metropolitan Organizing Strategy Enabling Strength (Detroit, Mich.); Michigan Muslim Community Council.; Michigan Russian Cultural Center.; Michigan Taiwanese American Organization.; Migrant Health Promotion (Organization); Motown Record Corporation -- History.; Muslim American Logic Institute.; New Bethel Baptist Church (Detroit, Mich.); New Detroit, Inc (Detroit, Mich.); Philippine Chamber of Commerce - Michigan.; Pokagon Band of Potawatomi.; St. Matthew's & St. Joseph's Episcopal Church (Detroit, Mich.); St. Sabbath the Sacrified Orthodox Monastery (Harper Woods, Mich.); St. Vladimir Orthodox Church (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Universal Hagar's Spiritual Church.; West Side Detroit Polish American Historical Society.; Word Of Faith International Christian Center (Southfield, Mich.); Yemeni American Net.; Keweenaw Bay Indian Community, Michigan.; El Vocero Hispano.; Forum & Link Newspaper.; Makarem, Julia.; Michigan Arab Times.; Muslim Observer.; Nordamerikanische Wochen-Post.; Russianmichigan.com.
- Ethnic Communities of Michigan Web Archives
  - 100 Black Men of Detroit, 2011
  - African American Cultural and Historical Museum of Washtenaw County, 2011
  - American Arab Chamber of Commerce, 2011
  - American Druze Society, 2011
  - American Federation of Ramallah-Palestine, 2010
  - American Muslim Society, 2010
  - American-Arab Anti-Discrimination Committee, 2012
  - American-Arab Anti-Discrimination Committee-Michigan, 2010
  - Ann Arbor Chinese Center of Michigan, 2013
  - Antiochian Basilica of St. Mary, 2010
  - Arab Community Center for Economic and Social Services, 2010
  - Arab America, 2011
  - Asian Pacific American Chamber of Commerce, 2011
  - Association of Chinese Americans-Detroit Chapter, 2011
  - Bay Mills Chippewa Indian Community, 2011
  - Chaldean American Ladies of Charity, 2010
  - Chippewa Ottawa Resource Authority, 2012
  - Council of Islamic Organizations in Michigan, 2011
  - Detroit Association of Black Organizations, 2011
  - El Vocero Hispano, 2012
  - Forum & Link, 2010
  - Grand Traverse Band of Ottawa and Chippewa Indians, 2010
  - Greater Grace Temple, 2011
  - Hartford Memorial Baptist Church (Detroit, Mich.), 2011
  - Heidelberg Project, 2013
  - Hype&Sou!-The Motown History, 2011
  - Islamic Center of America, 2011
  - Italian-American Club of Lansing, 2010
  - Judge Deborah Geraldine Bledsoe Ford, 2011
  - Keeweenaw Bay Indian Community, 2011
  - Lebanese American Heritage Club, 2010
  - Little River Band of Ottawa Indians in Manistee, Michigan, 2010
  - Little Traverse Bay Bands of Odawa Indians, 2010
  - Metropolitan Organizing Strategy Enabling Strength, 2012
  - Michigan Arab Times, 2011
  - Michigan Russian Cultural Center School, 2011
  - Michigan Taiwanese American Organization, 2011
  - Migrant Health Promotion, 2012
  - Muslim American Logic Institute, 2012
  - Muslim Observer, 2011
  - New Bethel Baptist Church (Detroit, Mich.), 2011
  - New Detroit, 2011
  - Nordamerikanische Wochen-Post, 2012
  - Nottawaseppi Huron Band of Potawatomi, 2010
  - Philippine Chamber of Commerce-Michigan, 2011
  - Pokagon Band of Potawatomi Indians, 2010
  - Reclaiming Identity: Dismantling Arab Stereotypes, 2012
  - Russian Michigan Yellow Pages, 2011
  - Saginaw Chippewa Indian Tribe, 2010
  - Sault Tribe of Chippewa Indians, 2010
  - St. Matthew's & St. Joseph's Episcopal Church (Detroit, Mich.), 2011
  - St. Sabbas Orthodox Monastery (Harper Woods, Mich.), 2011
  - St. Vladimir Orthodox Church (Dexter, Mich.), 2011
  - Universal Hagar's Spiritual Church--George H. Latimer-Knight Ministries International, 2011
  - West Side Detroit Polish American Historical Society, 2011
  - Word Of Faith International Christian Center (Southfield, Mich.), 2011
  - Yemeni American Net, 2011